scandinaviandesigncenter.com 2019-02-28

# Security and privacy policy at scandinaviandesigncenter.com

## Privacy Policy

Thank you for visiting our online shop. Protection of your privacy is very important to us. Below you will find extensive information about how we handle your data.

**1\. Access data and hosting**

You may visit our website without revealing any personal information. With every visit on the website, the web server stores automatically only a so-called server log file which contains e.g. the name of the requested file, your IP address, the date and time of the request, the volume of data transferred and the requesting provider (access data), and documents the request.

These access data are analysed exclusively for the purpose of ensuring the smooth operation of the website and improving our offer. This serves the protection of our legitimate interests in the proper presentation of our offer that are overriding in the process of balancing of interests. All access data are deleted no later than seven days after the end of your visit on our website.

**Third-party hosting services**  
Data are also processed by a third-party provider that we have engaged to render hosting and website presentation services on our behalf. This provider processes on its servers all data that are collected in the manner specified below when you visit our website or fill in forms made available for this purpose in our online shop. Data are processed on other servers only in the scope described herein.

This service provider is based in an EU or EEA member state.

**2\. Data collection and use for processing the contract  **

We collect personal data that you disclose to us whenever you place an order or contact us (e.g. via contact form or by email). Mandatory fields are marked as such because we absolutely need those data to perform the contract or process your contact request, and you would otherwise not be able to complete your order or send the contact request. It is evident in each input form what data are collected. We use the data that you disclose to us to perform the contract and process your enquiries. Upon contract completion, any further processing of your data will be restricted, and your data will be deleted upon expiry of any retention period applicable under relevant statutory regulations, unless you expressly consent to the further use of your data or we reserve the right to further use your data in the scope and manner permitted by law, of which we inform you in this notice.

**3\. Transfer of data**

For the purpose of contract performance, we disclose your data to the shipping company in the scope required for the delivery of the ordered goods. Depending on the payment service provider you have selected during the ordering process, we disclose the payment details collected for order processing purposes to the bank commissioned to handle the payment and, as the case may be, to the payment service provider commissioned by us or to the selected payment service. Some of those data are collected by the selected payment service providers themselves if you open an account with them. In such a case, during the ordering process, you must register with your payment service provider using your access data. In this respect, the privacy notice of the relevant payment service provider applies.

**Disclosure of data to a shipping provider**  
If, when or after placing your order, you have given your express consent to us doing so, we disclose your e-mail address and phone number to the selected shipping provider based on that consent, in order to enable the shipping provider to contact you to advise you of the delivery or agree with you the delivery details.

You may revoke your consent at any time by sending a message to the contact option described below or by directly notifying the shipping provider at the contact address specified below. After you revoke your consent, we will delete the data disclosed for this purpose, unless you expressly consent to the further use of your data or we reserve the right to further use your personal data in the scope and manner permitted by the law, of which we inform you in this notice.

Deutsche Post AG  
Charles-de-Gaulle-Str. 20  
53113  
Bonn, Germany

UPS Europe SPRL/BVBA  
Avenue Ariane 5  
1200 Brüssel, Belgium

**4\. Email newsletter**

**E-mail advertising if you subscribe to the newsletter**  
If you subscribe to our newsletter, we will regularly send you our e-mail newsletter based on your consent, using the data required or disclosed by you separately for this purpose.

You may unsubscribe from the newsletter service at any time. For this purpose you can either send a message to the contact option specified below or use the opt-out link in the newsletter. Upon unsubscription, we will delete your email address unless you have expressly consented to the further use of your data or we reserve the right to further use your personal data in the scope and manner permitted by the law, of which we inform you in this notice.

The newsletter is sent to you by our service provider who processes data on our behalf and to whom we disclose your email address.

This service provider is based in an EU or EEA member state.

**5\. Integration of the Trusted Shops Trustbadge**

We have integrated the Trusted Shops Trustbadge on this website in order to display our Trusted Shops Trustmark and offer the Trusted Shops products to customers after placing an order.

This serves the protection of our legitimate interests in the optimal marketing of our offer that are overriding in the process of balancing of interests. The Trustbadge and the advertised trust badge services are offered by Trusted Shops GmbH, Subbelrather Str. 15C, 50823 Cologne, Germany.  
With every use of the Trustbadge, the web server automatically saves a so-called server log file which contains e.g. your IP address, the date and time of the request, the volume of data transferred and the requesting provider (access data), and documents the request. Those access data are not analysed and are automatically overwritten no later than seven days after the end of your website visit.  
Other personal data are transferred to Trusted Shops only if you decide to use or have already registered to use Trusted Shops products after placing an order. In such a case, the contract concluded between you and Trusted Shops applies.

**6\. Cookies and web-analysis**

To improve the user experience on our website and enable you to use its certain features in order to show suitable products or conduct market research, some pages of this website use the so-called cookies. This serves the protection of our legitimate interests in the optimised presentation of our offer that are overriding in the process of balancing of interests. A cookie is a small text file which is stored automatically on your end device. Some of the cookies we use are deleted after you close the browser session, i.e. when you close the browser (that’s the so-called session cookies). Other cookies are stored in your end-user device and enable us to recognise your browser when you visit us again (persistent cookies). To check the cookie storage period, you can use the Overview function in the cookie settings of your web browser. You can configure your browser for it to inform you whenever a page uses cookies and decide on a case-by-case basis whether to accept or reject the cookies on a given website or generally. Every browser has a different policy for managing the cookie settings. The browser’s policy is described in the Help menu of every browser and explains how you can change your cookie settings. To find out how to change the settings in your browser, see the links below:  
Internet Explorer™: http://windows.microsoft.com/de-DE/windows-vista/Block-or-allow-cookies  
Safari™: https://support.apple.com/kb/ph21411?locale=de_DE  
Chrome™: http://support.google.com/chrome/bin/answer.py?hl=de&hlrm=en&answer=95647  
Firefox™ https://support.mozilla.org/de/kb/cookies-erlauben-und-ablehnen  
Opera™ : http://help.opera.com/Windows/10.20/de/cookies.html

Please note that disabling cookies may limit your access to some features of our website.

This website also uses the so-called DoubleClick cookie for the purpose of Google Analytics (see below). The DoubleClick cookie enables the recognition of your browser as you visit other websites. The information generated automatically by the cookie about your visit to this website will be transmitted to and stored on a Google server in the United States. By means of IP anonymisation enabled on this website, the IP address will be shortened before being transmitted within the area of member states of the European Union or other parties to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases, the full IP address will be sent to a Google server in the USA and shortened there. Google will not join the anonymised IP address, transmitted from your browser through Google Analytics, with any other data held by Google.

Google will use this information to compile reports about your website activities and to provide other services related to the use of the website. This serves the protection of our legitimate interests in the optimal marketing of our website that are overriding in the process of balancing of interests. In addition, Google may transfer this information to third parties from time to time if this is required by law or if third parties process such data on behalf of Google.

Google Double Click is offered by Google LLC. (www.google.com).   
Google LLC is headquartered in the USA and is certified to the EU-US Privacy Shield. You will see the up-to-date certificate [here](https://www.privacyshield.gov/list). Based on this agreement between the USA and the European Commission, the latter has recognised entities certified to the Privacy Shield as those ensuring an adequate level of data protection.

You can disable the DoubleClick cookie via [this link](https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated?hl=en). In addition, you can obtain information about the setting of cookies from the Digital Advertising Alliance [link to: http://www.aboutads.info/] and accordingly adapt the settings of your browser. Finally, you can configure your browser for it to inform you about the setting of cookies and decide on a case-by-case basis whether to accept or reject the cookies on a given website or generally. Please note that disabling cookies may limit your access to some features of our website.

**Using of Google (Universal) Analytics for web analytics**  
For the purpose of website analytics, this website uses Google (Universal) Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google LLC (www.google.com). This serves the protection of our legitimate interests in the optimised presentation of our offer that are overriding in the process of balancing of interests. Google (Universal) Analytics uses methods, like e.g. cookies, that enable an analysis of your use of the website. The information collected automatically by cookies about your use of this website are as a rule transmitted to and stored on a Google server in the United States. At the same time, as IP anonymisation is enabled on this website, the IP address will be shortened before being transmitted within the area of member states of the European Union or other parties to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases, the full IP address will be sent to a Google server in the USA and shortened there. Generally, Google does not associate the anonymised IP address, transmitted from your browser through Google Analytics, with any other data held by Google.

Google LLC is headquartered in the USA and is certified to the EU-US-Privacy Shield. You will see the up-to-date certificate [here](https://www.privacyshield.gov/list). Based on this agreement between the USA and the European Commission, the latter has recognised entities certified to the Privacy Shield as those ensuring an adequate level of data protection.

You may prevent the data generated by cookies and related to your use of the website (incl. your IP address) from being recorded and processed by Google by downloading and installing the browser plugin available through the following link: http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=de

Alternatively to the browser plugin, you may click this link, to prevent Google Analytics from recording your data on this website in the future. In this process, an opt-out cookie will be stored on your end-user device. If you clear your cookies, you will have to click the link again.

**Use of Application Insights (Azure)**

This website uses Application Insights, a web analytics service provided by Microsoft, Inc. ("Microsoft"). Application Insights uses "cookies", to help the website analyze how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Microsoft on servers in the USA. Microsoft will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage. Microsoft may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Microsoft's behalf.

**Use of other types of cookies:**

Scand. Design Online AB uses strictly necessary, analytical, functional and targeting cookies. Here we will outline the types of cookies that we use as well as their functions for us.

**Strictly necessary cookies**

Cookie: Azure  
Purpose: To keep all content on our website, such as text, images and scripts. This data storage is done through a so-called content delivery network that optimizes user convenience for visitors worldwide. [Read Azure’s privacy policy here.](https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/support/legal/)

Cookie: Pingdom AB  
Purpose: Cookies used to monitor page load timing and services uptime. It does not contain any user identification information. [Read Pingdom’s privacy policy here.](https://www.pingdom.com/legal/cookie-policy)

**Targeting Cookies:**

Cookie: Peerius (EPiServer)  
Peerius use cookies to track the activity if customers on the site in order to help us provide the most relevant product recommendations to you based on products you have previously viewed or purchased and the categories in which you have previously expressed an interest. [Read EPiServer’s privacy policy here.](https://www.episerver.com/legal/privacy-statement)

Cookie: Awin/Zanox   
Purpose: To enforce the agreements from our affiliate program. By placing ads on the websites of our affiliate partners, we promote promotion of our website. When visitors then make a purchase through one of these ads, these partners receive a commission. [Read Awin’s privacy policy here.](https://www.awin.com/gb/legal/privacy-policy)

Cookie: Criteo   
We use Criteo to show online ad banners after visitors visited our website. The content of these personalized banners is generated based on the click behavior on our website. If desired, visitors can still make their purchases at a later date. [Read Criteo’s privacy policy here.](https://www.criteo.com/privacy/)

**Functional Cookies:**

Cookie: Google Optimize  
We use Google Optimize as a split testing tool to perform A/B testing on our website to improve its usability and effectiveness. Google Optimize uses cookies to anonymously identify visitors, to enable them to show the same variant to you over several visits, and to collect statistics and the performance of each variant. [Read Google Optimize's privacy policy here](https://support.google.com/optimize/answer/6230273?hl=en).

Cookie: Hotjar  
We use Hotjar to improve the user experience on our websites. Hotjar collects anonymous usage information from our website, including the pages you visit. Hotjar does not collect form submissions or any personal information. [Read Hotjar’s privacy policy here](https://www.hotjar.com/privacy).

**7\. Advertisement for marketing purposes**

**Google AdWords remarketing**  
We use Google AdWords to advertise our website in Google search results and on third-party websites. For this purpose, when you visit our website, the so-called remarketing cookie of Google is set on your browser, which allows the automatic displaying of interest-based advertising using a pseudonymous cookie ID and information about your website visits. This serves the protection of our legitimate interests in the optimal marketing of our website that are overriding in the process of balancing of interests.

Any data processing that goes beyond that scope takes place only if you have allowed Google to associate your web and app browsing history with your Google account and to use information from your Google account to personalise ads that you see across the web. If, in such a case, you visit our website while being signed in to Google, Google will use your data together with Google Analytics data to build and define audience lists for cross-device remarketing. For this purpose, Google will temporarily join your data with Google Analytics data to build audiences.

Google AdWords remarketing is offered by Google LLC (www.google.com). Die Google LLC is headquartered in the USA und and is certified to the EU-US-Privacy Shield. You will see the up-to-date certificate here [link to: https://www.privacyshield.gov/list]. Based on this agreement between the USA and the European Commission, the latter has recognised entities certified to the Privacy Shield as those ensuring an adequate level of data protection.

You can disable the remarketing cookie via [this link](https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated?hl=en). In addition, you can obtain information about the setting of cookies from the [Digital Advertising Alliance](http://www.aboutads.info/) and accordingly adapt the settings of your browser.

**8\. Social media plugins**

**Using of social network plugins of Facebook, Google, Instagram, Pinterest using the "2-click solution"**  
To increase the level of protection of your data during your visit to our website, the site uses the plugins using the so-called “2 click solution“. This ensures that when you call a page of our website, which contains such plugins, no link to the servers of a social network provider is established yet. Only when you enable the plugins, your browser will establish a direct link to the servers of the social network provider.

The content of the given plugin is then transferred by the relevant provider directly to your browser and integrated within the page you are viewing. This allows the providers to obtain information that you viewed a relevant page of our website in your browser, also if you do not have an account with the relevant provider or are currently not signed in. This information (including your IP address) will be sent from your browser directly to the relevant provider’s server (which may be in the USA) and stored there. If you interact with the plugins, e.g. click the 'Like' or 'Share' button, this information will be also sent directly to the provider’s server and stored there. In addition, the information will be published on the social network page and your contacts will be able to see it.

To find out more about the purpose and scope of collection, further processing and use of the data by the providers, and to learn about the available contact options and your rights in this respect and how you can customise your browser to better protect your privacy, please see the data privacy policies of the providers:

http://www.facebook.com/policy.php  
http://www.google.com/intl/de/+/policy/+1button.html  
https://help.instagram.com/155833707900388  
https://about.pinterest.com/de/privacy-policy

**9\. Sending rating reminders by email**

**Rating reminder by Trusted Shops**  
If, when or after placing your order, you have given us your express consent to doing so, we will disclose your e-mail address to Trusted Shops GmbH, Subbelrather Str. 15c, 50823 Cologne, Germany (www.trustedshops.com), so that they can email you a rating reminder.

You may revoke your consent at any time by sending a message to the contact option specified below or directly to Trusted Shops.

**10\. Links**  
The site www.scandinaviandesigncenter.com may include links to other websites which do not fall under our supervision. We cannot accept any responsibility for the protection of privacy or the content of these websites, but we offer these links to make it easier for our visitors to find more information about specific subjects.

**11\. Contact possibilities and your rights**

You are entitled to obtain free-of-charge information concerning data stored about your person and, as the case may be, to correct, restrict the processing, enable the portability of, or delete those data.

If you have any questions about how we collect, process or use your personal data, want to enquire about, correct, block or delete your data, or withdraw any consents you have given, or opt-out of any particular data use, please contact our in-house data protection officer 

Bank Bergström  
Amerikavägen 10  
39356 Kalmar, Sweden  

When contacting us, we require you to be able to identify yourself in order to prove that you are in fact the person you are inquiring information about. This means either a valid copy of an ID, drivers license or similar, or contacting us from the Email address that you have signed up to our newsletter with, or used when placing your order.

You may also submit a complaint to the responsible data protection supervisory authority.

********************************************************************  
**Right to object**  
If we process personal data as described above to protect our legitimate interests that are overriding in the process of balancing of interests, you may object to such data processing with future effect. If your data are processed for direct marketing purposes, you may exercise this right at any time as described above. If your data are processed for other purposes, you have the right to object only on grounds relating to your particular situation.

After you have exercised your right to object, we will no longer process your personal data for such purposes unless we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing which override your interests, rights and freedoms or for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.

This does not apply to the processing of personal data for direct marketing purposes. In such a case we will no longer process your personal data for such purposes.

********************************************************************

_Last updated: May 22nd 2018._
